Guide to the Schauffler family papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Schauffler family papers
1890-1983
MS 1389
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
95
Correspondence, subject files, printed materials, and photographs documenting the lives of members of the Schauffler family.
Schauffler family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elizabeth Lyman, 1982, 1985, 2000; gift of Peter Schauffler,1985, 2000; gift of Richard Schauffler, 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
The original accession is open for research. Accession 2000-M-128 is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, subject files, printed materials, and photographs documenting the lives of members of the Schauffler family.
- Original accession
  - Correspondence
    - 1867-1919 (Box 1)
    - 1920-1940 (Box 2)
    - 1930s (Box 3)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 4)
    - n.d. (Box 5)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 6)
    - 1970s (Box 7)
    - n.d. (Box 8–10)
    - Christmas cards (Box 11–15)
  - Family papers (Box 16–37)
  - Schauffler, Mamie Page
    - General (Box 38–45)
    - A.F.S.C. (Box 46–48)
    - C.I.V. (Box 49–53)
    - COSERV (Box 54)
    - Refugees (Box 55–63)
    - S.A.S. (Box 64–69)
    - W.U.S. (Box 70)
    - Professional files (Box 71–72)
  - Organizations (Box 73–78)
  - Schauffler, Bennett F. (Box 79–81)
  - Photographs (Box 82–86)
  - Printed materials (Box 87–92)
- Additional material, Accession 2000-M-128
  Conditions Governing Access
  The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
  - Signed photographs, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - B. and M. wedding Squam, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Cochin and Stockholm and Scausen, 1960?; 1972? (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, Circa 1912-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, notes, and postcards, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Portraits and others, 1913-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - Sumatra and others, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - Marjorie at college, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - family friends, 1916-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - B. F. S. Highland Park, college, friends, Europe, et cetera, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - Norway, the lake, North Carolina, Stockholm, Athens, and Piraeus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - North Carolina, Stockholm, Amsterdam, Gata Canal, Lillehammer, Nile, Yugoslavia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs - North Carolina, Norway, Egypt, Copenhagen, Venice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs - Stockholm, Paris, Amsterdam, Finland, Nepal, India, Sumatra, et cetera, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs - Copenhagen, North Carolina, Egypt, Greece, India, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Album, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diaries and address books
    - Diaries, 1922, 1923; 1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1916, 1925; 1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, 1912, 1918; 1918 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Address books, 1902, Undated; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, 1913, 1924, 1928; 1924; 1928 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Diaries, 1915, 1920, 1923, 1924; 1920; 1923; 1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Diaries, 1914, 1921; 1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Le Morte d'Arthur, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gertrude Sayer portrait, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Album, 1899-1920 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Address book, 1911-1915 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Checkontrol - combined check record and budget control, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Wills and probates, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pete's letters, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Portraits and paintings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous papers - portraits, articles, letters, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographs - Bennet Schauffler's picture of Grandma Manuel, 1912-1931 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - Schauffler family, 1884-1926 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - Christmas, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Page family and friends at the lake, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - travel, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - travel, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Photographs - clippings, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Maps and sketches, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Greek and Roman, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - miscellaneous, 1893-1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - travel, 1974-1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - notes and passports, 1952-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - travel, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Life insurance book, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Letters and documents, 1879-1940 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Daily reminder book, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Marjorie P. Schauffler Council for International Visitors scrapbook, 1954-1960 (Box 4)
  - Photograph album, 1916-1918, undated (Box 5)